<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts | Academic</title>
    <link>https://barutwanayo-syldie.github.io/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://barutwanayo-syldie.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Posts</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 20:56:54 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://barutwanayo-syldie.github.io/images/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Posts</title>
      <link>https://barutwanayo-syldie.github.io/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Links to scholarly and bibliometric resources </title>
      <link>https://barutwanayo-syldie.github.io/post/link/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 20:56:54 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://barutwanayo-syldie.github.io/post/link/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.elibrary.ru/defaultx.asp&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt; eLibrary&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://scholar.google.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt; Google Scholar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://orcid.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt; ORCID&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mendeley.com/?interaction_required=true&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt; Mendeley&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.researchgate.net/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt; ResearchGate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.academia.edu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt; Academia.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt; arXiv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt; github&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coronavirus  in Moscow</title>
      <link>https://barutwanayo-syldie.github.io/post/university/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 22:42:34 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://barutwanayo-syldie.github.io/post/university/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Moscow expands the list of those who will soon be able to be vaccinated against coronavirus with the domestic drug Sputnik V. From December 28 it will include employees of the housing and utilities sector, catering and others. In addition, according to the mayor of the capital Sergey Sobyanin, vaccination points will also work during the New Year holidays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;COVID-19 vaccination points will be open during the New Year holidays. To allow as many Muscovites as possible to take advantage of free time and get vaccinated, starting Monday, December 28, 2020, we open an appointment for vaccination for new categories of city residents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are those employed in the areas of housing, public catering, sports and law enforcement, including police, prosecutors, courts and others,&amp;rdquo; - wrote the head of the city in his blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He noted that vaccination is also available for volunteers and those employed by nonprofit and religious organizations. &amp;ldquo;During the New Year and Christmas season, they have especially a lot of interaction with people. It will be good if they protect themselves in advance from the risk of getting covid,&amp;rdquo; the mayor believes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earlier the mayor of Moscow expressed the hope that the vaccination will become more widespread and will be available in the coming weeks to all the inhabitants of the Russian capital. At present this free service is available to employees of education, health, culture and trade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, employees of the media, multifunctional centers of public services, social services, transport, energy and industry may get vaccinated upon request. Representatives of these sectors will receive an SMS-notification with an invitation to vaccination and instructions to sign up for the procedure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The city authorities plan to vaccinate at least half of the city residents - 6-7 million people. It is also supposed to consider the issue of preferences for those who have already been vaccinated. The Mayor of Moscow has earlier pointed out that after vaccination the city&amp;rsquo;s inhabitants may return to life without restrictions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coronavirus vaccination in the capital began earlier this month, on December 5. In 12 days, according to TASS, about 15 thousand people have been vaccinated. Registration for the procedure is done electronically - on the city portal mos.ru.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, it is possible to sign up through the medical portal EMIAS. The registration is open six months in advance. In total there are 70 vaccination centers in Moscow, which are open daily from 8 a.m. to 8 p.m.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vaccination is allowed to those who have no symptoms of acute respiratory viral infections, who have not had coronavirus, and who are not ill during the procedure. In addition, vaccination is not recommended for pregnant women and people under 18 years of age.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the same time, elderly patients will be able to undergo it in the near future. Earlier, the head of the Gamaleya Center Alexander Gintsburg, who developed the drug for vaccination, told about the results of the drug trial on older people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The trial, in which a large sample of Moscow population aged over 60 years was involved, was completed a few days ago and today the scientific results of the test were summarized and presented to the Ministry of Health in the prescribed form &amp;ldquo;- said Gintsburg.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He emphasized that the results are good. &amp;ldquo;One can state with a certain degree of certainty that in the coming days a decision will be made on the possibility of using the Sputnik V vaccine to vaccinate the population starting from the age of 18 and without age restrictions,&amp;rdquo; Gintsburg believes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One way or another, according to him, about 650 thousand doses of Sputnik V vaccine have already been released to civilian circulation. The same amount is still in the warehouses. He added that about 1.5 million people would be supplied with vaccine by the New Year. At the end of January-February, it is planned that production will reach 5-6 million doses of vaccines per month&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Burundi is a Central African country</title>
      <link>https://barutwanayo-syldie.github.io/post/life/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 22:25:44 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://barutwanayo-syldie.github.io/post/life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Burundi is a Central African country
which covers an area of 27,834 km2
of which 25,200 terrestrial. It is a country where
Agriculture employs 90% of the population. The objectives for the protection of
the environment are essential and pass
inevitably through education about
the environment (ErE).
We believe, however, that traditionally the people
of Burundi had customs aimed at preserving its
environment and that it was developing in this respect a certain
number of values. It seems to us that it is essential
revalorise traditional knowledge and practices in order to
any action in EWE in Burundi. It is to be feared, indeed,
that in contact with other cultures, certain elements of the
Burundian culture have faded.
It also seems that education on
the environment can spread thanks to the action of the
women who have a key role in the education of children and
Burundi.
Traditional Burundian education
In ancient Burundi, children were educated for the
function or position held by their parents.
The blacksmith&amp;rsquo;s child became a blacksmith, the hunter&amp;rsquo;s child became a hunter.
became a hunter. Mothers and fathers took care of the
respectively of their boys and girls in order to
teach them a trade.
Moral values were of considerable importance,
Examples include the Ubuntu, the Ubushingantahe, a male
of value is a worthy, charitable, responsible man,
justice-loving. In short, a man who is a reference for
its environment.
Alice Nindorera
Design Office and
of the Programmes of
Education
Secondary of
Burundi
Aspects of cultural heritage
contributing to relative education
to the environment in Burundi
ENVIRONMENTAL EDUCATION, Vol. 5, 2004-2005 109
110 Alice Nindorera
Certain practices were conveyed through taboos and prohibitions.
For example, it was prescribed to respect forests and sacred animals and
that by this obligation, the forests were preserved.
The contact of the Burundian culture with other cultures
With colonisation, traditional habits were abandoned in the
taking advantage of modern practices.
In parallel with a more or less tenacious traditionalism, there is a
new trend towards synthesis between the existing culture and the new
new influences, sometimes even towards an almost total abandonment of the
ancestral heritage. (Manirambona, 1997, p. 11).
Some research (e.g. Bigawa et al., 2000) concludes that
that plants and animals once respected are no longer respected. Some species
are threatened with extinction. Currently, the traditional way of
conservation of biodiversity, which was achieved through the &amp;ldquo;in situ&amp;rdquo; existence of
Sacred groves and sacred animals tend to disappear. A more rational mode
of &amp;ldquo;ex-situ&amp;rdquo; conservation is manifested in the form of sacred woods, groves
resources, genetic resources, agroforestry, and medicinal plants.
in an enclosure.
It seems urgent to us to revalorise certain practices or beliefs
for the respect of the environment. We will take up here some
examples of local practices for the protection of fauna and flora and the
flora.
The fauna
Wildlife held a considerable place in Burundian culture. Some
animals were highly respected for their beauty and their role in society.
This is the case of the cow (inka). In addition to its dietary and medical role, it
intervenes in the weaving and consolidation of family ties since it
is a basis for the dowry at the wedding. Panthera leopard skin
pardus serves as a costume for the dancers. Some birds (the ombrette or
the Dominican widow, for example) as well as the leopard, the hare, the python,
etc. were used in traditional medicine.
Through education, mothers prohibited children from killing animals.
For example, it was forbidden to kill the lizard. The Barundi used to say: Wishe
umuserebanyi, nyoko aca acika amabere (if you kill the lizard, your mummy will lose the lizard)
her breasts). Nobody dared to kill the widowed African wagtail for free,
Motacilla aguimp. This one, like the sheep, represented God.
(Imana). There were animals of good omen and others of bad omen.
For example, our ancestors believed that the cry of an owl predicted the death of an
ASPECTS OF CULTURAL HERITAGE CONTRIBUTING TO THE ERE AU BURUNDI 111
family member. However, a Rundi proverb says: Wica isake, ntiwica
ico yabitse (you can kill the rooster, but you can&amp;rsquo;t kill what it predicted). This
was a kind of ploy to avoid killing these people.
animals that heralded unfortunate events.
The Ox Heron, Bulbucus ibis - inyange, is praised for its beauty in
songs and tales. It is a bird that has a lot of importance especially
for breeders. &amp;ldquo;Given the importance that the Inyange had in our culture, the
killing was a cr&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
