<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts | Academic</title>
    <link>https://barutwanayo-syldie.github.io/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://barutwanayo-syldie.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Posts</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 20:56:54 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://barutwanayo-syldie.github.io/images/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Posts</title>
      <link>https://barutwanayo-syldie.github.io/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>ссылки на научые и библиометрические ресурсы </title>
      <link>https://barutwanayo-syldie.github.io/post/link/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 20:56:54 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://barutwanayo-syldie.github.io/post/link/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.elibrary.ru/defaultx.asp&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt; eLibrary&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://scholar.google.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt; Google Scholar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://orcid.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt; ORCID&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mendeley.com/?interaction_required=true&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt; Mendeley&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.researchgate.net/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt; ResearchGate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.academia.edu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt; Academia.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt; arXiv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt; github&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coronavirus  in Moscow</title>
      <link>https://barutwanayo-syldie.github.io/post/university/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 22:42:34 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://barutwanayo-syldie.github.io/post/university/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Moscow expands the list of those who will soon be able to be vaccinated against coronavirus with the domestic drug Sputnik V. From December 28 it will include employees of the housing and utilities sector, catering and others. In addition, according to the mayor of the capital Sergey Sobyanin, vaccination points will also work during the New Year holidays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;COVID-19 vaccination points will be open during the New Year holidays. To allow as many Muscovites as possible to take advantage of free time and get vaccinated, starting Monday, December 28, 2020, we open an appointment for vaccination for new categories of city residents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are those employed in the areas of housing, public catering, sports and law enforcement, including police, prosecutors, courts and others,&amp;rdquo; - wrote the head of the city in his blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He noted that vaccination is also available for volunteers and those employed by nonprofit and religious organizations. &amp;ldquo;During the New Year and Christmas season, they have especially a lot of interaction with people. It will be good if they protect themselves in advance from the risk of getting covid,&amp;rdquo; the mayor believes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earlier the mayor of Moscow expressed the hope that the vaccination will become more widespread and will be available in the coming weeks to all the inhabitants of the Russian capital. At present this free service is available to employees of education, health, culture and trade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, employees of the media, multifunctional centers of public services, social services, transport, energy and industry may get vaccinated upon request. Representatives of these sectors will receive an SMS-notification with an invitation to vaccination and instructions to sign up for the procedure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The city authorities plan to vaccinate at least half of the city residents - 6-7 million people. It is also supposed to consider the issue of preferences for those who have already been vaccinated. The Mayor of Moscow has earlier pointed out that after vaccination the city&amp;rsquo;s inhabitants may return to life without restrictions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coronavirus vaccination in the capital began earlier this month, on December 5. In 12 days, according to TASS, about 15 thousand people have been vaccinated. Registration for the procedure is done electronically - on the city portal mos.ru.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, it is possible to sign up through the medical portal EMIAS. The registration is open six months in advance. In total there are 70 vaccination centers in Moscow, which are open daily from 8 a.m. to 8 p.m.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vaccination is allowed to those who have no symptoms of acute respiratory viral infections, who have not had coronavirus, and who are not ill during the procedure. In addition, vaccination is not recommended for pregnant women and people under 18 years of age.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the same time, elderly patients will be able to undergo it in the near future. Earlier, the head of the Gamaleya Center Alexander Gintsburg, who developed the drug for vaccination, told about the results of the drug trial on older people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The trial, in which a large sample of Moscow population aged over 60 years was involved, was completed a few days ago and today the scientific results of the test were summarized and presented to the Ministry of Health in the prescribed form &amp;ldquo;- said Gintsburg.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He emphasized that the results are good. &amp;ldquo;One can state with a certain degree of certainty that in the coming days a decision will be made on the possibility of using the Sputnik V vaccine to vaccinate the population starting from the age of 18 and without age restrictions,&amp;rdquo; Gintsburg believes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One way or another, according to him, about 650 thousand doses of Sputnik V vaccine have already been released to civilian circulation. The same amount is still in the warehouses. He added that about 1.5 million people would be supplied with vaccine by the New Year. At the end of January-February, it is planned that production will reach 5-6 million doses of vaccines per month&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life</title>
      <link>https://barutwanayo-syldie.github.io/post/life/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 22:25:44 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://barutwanayo-syldie.github.io/post/life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;life not easy that is why we have to take care our life and work so hard in order to keep our life.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
